Whenever my character is wall sliding, I'm going to change that relative location.
So if I head back to my player blueprint.
When I'm on a wall.
All right.
I'm just going to drag up this node and I'll set relative location.
I want to set the relative location of the sprite.
And we're only going to be changing its location in the x axis.
So just right click on here and it will split open.
And we want to keep whatever values our character has in its relative location in the Y and Z axis.
So if we just drag off the sprite and or get relative.
Location.
Right click on this and we'll split structure pin and you've got Y to Y and Z to Z.
Then for X, I found the value of 50 works quite well for the spread.
If you're using a difference right, you may need to use a different value.
But basically the higher the value this is, the closer the character is going to be to the wall.
You may need to play around to get the perfect value.
Then when a character is off the wall again, going to set their relative location back to their normal
values.
So I'm just going to copy this and paste this here.
We can delete this print shrink.
I think by default my character is no more relative.
Location is 20 in the x axis, so I'm just going to change it back to 20.
I want you to compile and test that.
This all works.
When I saw that on the wall, I'm going to be much closer.
So that looks a lot better.
Hello.
The next feature we're going to implement is a wall slide jump.
So whenever my character is sliding along a wall, if they jump, we're going to launch them in the
opposite direction they're facing in order to set that up.
If we head over to the player.
Beep and we can just come in all these notes and call the ball slide.
And we will go back to our jump.
So I'm just going to select it and move it all the way here.
So if my player character passes the jump on, if that's flying along the wall to do things a bit differently
if we have a branch.
And the condition of this product is going to be slight.
If this is false, then we'll just do our job.
Arthur, if this is true, I'll break the link here by just right clicking and break the link.
We want to launch our character somewhat for launch character.
I just moved the nodes around, so I had a bit more space.
So if my character is wall sliding along the wall and they jump, we're going to launch our character
over at Launch Velocity, just right click and split the structure pin and just click X, Y and Z override.
So in the Z axis, which will be launching our character upwards, I found a valley of 750 works well.
So we're going to launch our character up 750 units in terms of the x axis, depending whether my character
is on the left or the right of the wall.
It's going to depend what direction we're going to launch them.
So in order to do that, we can right click for Get forward Vector.
This will get the whoops, not this one.
I'm going to look for get actor forward vector.
This will get the four direction that our character is facing.
We just want to right click on this return value and the split structure pin as we're only concerned
with the value in the x axis and we just want to drag up here for multiply.
And multiply this by a -40 and then put the number that you want to launch the character.
So I'm going to pull up 1000.
And hook us up to X so this will not work out to negatively whatever direction they're facing.
So if they're facing right then on the left and if they're facing the left, then I want them to the
right.
We can just go compile save and I'm just going to duplicate this wall.
So I press control C, then control V.
And if I could play, if I could the longest walk and press spacebar launch me in the opposite direction.
I get on this wall and press spacebar will launch me in the opposite direction.
I've noticed that when my character is on the wall and I just jump off it.
They don't really have much control and it kind of feels a bit weird to fix that.
We go back to our lab and go over to character movement under details.
If you look for air control, just make this have a value of 0.7.
So let's go from a value of 0 to 1.
The higher the value this is, the more control the player character is going to have when they're falling
in the air.
So I'm just going to pile and save that.
And try jumping.
Sliding again.
It's a bit more control when I do that now.
Quick tip, but it's kind of blurry when I need to quickly and do stuff like that in order to fix that.
Just go to edit and go product settings and then get a motion blur and just leave this unchecked.
And then it should not be as blurry.